canadacouncil.ca 2019-12-21

# Privacy Notice | The Canada Council for the Arts

The [_Privacy Act_](https://laws-lois.justice.gc.ca/eng/acts/P-21/FullText.html) governs the collection and use of personal information and how it’s protected by the Canada Council for the Arts. As described by the Act, personal information means any information about an identifiable individual. This notice does not apply to Canada Council employees’ personal information.

This Privacy Notice describes the Canada Council’s privacy practices as they relate to personal information, and applies to:

  * all information requested, collected and retained with your knowledge and consent to further the purpose of Canada Council services, programs and activities;
  * each of the Canada Council’s affiliated sites ([publiclendingright.ca](https://publiclendingright.ca/), [ccunesco.ca](https://en.ccunesco.ca/); [artbank.ca](https://artbank.ca/)); and
  * the [online portal](https://apply.canadacouncil.ca/?_ga=2.105220554.832715157.1545054931-1996032459.1462803336).

Your personal information is collected and administered in keeping with the following authorities:

  * the [_Canada Council for the Arts Act_](http://laws-lois.justice.gc.ca/eng/acts/C-2/index.html) _section 8;_
  * the [_Privacy Act_](http://laws-lois.justice.gc.ca/eng/acts/P-21/index.html);
  * [_Employment Equity Act_](https://laws-lois.justice.gc.ca/eng/acts/E-5.401/index.html) (sections 4.4; 5; and 9);
  * [_Canadian Human Rights Act_](https://laws-lois.justice.gc.ca/eng/acts/h-6/page-1.html) (section 16);
  * Treasury Board Secretariat policies, directives and guidelines on protection of personal information and, information management; and
  * Canada Council’s retention and disposition schedules.

_The Canada Council for the Arts reserves the right to modify this notice at any time.   You will be notified of modifications by a popup message._ An updated Privacy Notice will supersede earlier versions and will also apply to personal information previously provided to us.

When possible, the Canada Council will collect the personal information for an administrative purpose directly from you, unless otherwise required or pursuant to the [_Privacy Act_](http://laws-lois.justice.gc.ca/eng/acts/P-21/index.html). The nature of the information required will depend on your relationship with the Canada Council.  Any personal information shall be used for business purposes or for a purpose consistent with the original collection.  No personal information shall be collected unless it relates directly to the operating program, service or activity of the Canada Council.

Most of the personal information we process is provided directly by you for one of the following reasons:

  * When you apply to a Canada Council program or activity, or provide us with information as an applicant;
  * When you create an account using the [online portal](https://apply.canadacouncil.ca/?_ga=2.154768696.1619376462.1548165805-1996032459.1462803336);
  * When you apply for a job, or position on one of our committees, commissions (PLR, CCUNESCO), or advisory groups;
  * When you complete the [voluntary self-identification](https://canadacouncil.ca/funding/grants/guide/create-your-account) information;
  * When you make an enquiry or provide [public feedback](https://canadacouncil.ca/about/public-accountability/public-feedback);
  * When you subscribe to our mailing list;
  * When you participate in a survey or research project;
  * When you [donate](https://canadacouncil.ca/funding/prizes/donors#more) to the Canada Council for the Arts;
  * When you access the Canada Council websites; or
  * When you respond to a Request for Proposal (RFP), Request for Quote (RFQ) or contracting services.

We may receive personal information indirectly, when…

  * an applicant refers to you in their application;
  * an employee provides your contact details as an emergency contact;
  * you are nominated for a prize; or
  * a partnership program with arts and cultural funding agencies, is created through [CCUNESCO network initiatives](https://en.ccunesco.ca/networks), or with Canadian government institutions.

## Access or corrections to your personal information

The _Privacy Act_ provides people with the general right to access information that is held about them by the Council. [To access your personal information](https://canadacouncil.ca/about/public-accountability/access-to-information-and-privacy-acts) in accordance with the Act address your request to the Access to Information and Privacy (ATIP) Coordinator.

To correct or add to your personal information that we maintain, you may either make corrections by logging into the online portal, or submit the completed Record Correction Request Form to the ATIP Coordinator who will address your concerns.  All corrections and notations are made in accordance with the [Directive on Personal Information Requests and Correction of Personal Information](https://www.tbs-sct.gc.ca/pol/doc-eng.aspx?id=32590).

The Canada Council may correct contact information that contains typing errors in the following fields: address, city, or province. The purpose is to ensure the Canada Council is able to contact you and that its statistical reports reflect accurate information. 

Requests, questions, comments, concerns or complaints you may have regarding the administration of the _Privacy Act_ and this Privacy Notice should be directed to:

Access to Information and Privacy Coordinator

Canada Council for the Arts

150 Elgin St. P.O. Box 1047

Ottawa, Ontario K1P 5V8

E-mail: [atip-aiprp@canadacouncil.ca](mailto:atip-aiprp@canadacouncil.ca)

Telephone : 613-566-4414, ext. 4696

Toll free: 1-800-263-5588, ext. 4696 or

Fax: (613) 566-4390

TTY : 1-866-585-5559 (toll free)

Types of personal information and retention: [Personal Information Bank ](https://www.canada.ca/en/treasury-board-secretariat/services/access-information-privacy/access-information/information-about-programs-information-holdings/standard-personal-information-banks.html) PRN 901

If you are not satisfied with the Canada Council's response to your privacy concern, you may contact the [Office of the Privacy Commissioner](https://www.priv.gc.ca/en/contact-the-opc/) by telephone:

Toll-free: 1-800-282-1376  
Phone: (819) 994-5444  
TTY: (819) 994-6591

## How we use your information

### When you apply to a Canada Council program or activity, or provide us with information as an applicant.

The application, forms, final reports or any [other required documentation](https://canadacouncil.ca/funding/grants/guide/apply-to-programs) submitted to a program is used to:

  * review assess and make a recommendation on your application and required documentation in the [assessment process](https://canadacouncil.ca/funding/grants/guide/apply-to-programs);
  * confirm funding sources with other Canadian arts funders, including federal, provincial or municipal government institutions;
  * disclose information consistent with that program’s guideline to appropriate employees or where the Canada Council has established a partnership program;
  * support equal access to resources, opportunities or benefits through [diverse and accessible programs](https://canadacouncil.ca/commitments/equity) using specific measures to ensure fairness;
  * collect additional information, including banking information, social insurance number (SIN), when you receive or qualify for funding for a: 
    * program;
    * prize; or
    * PLR payment.
  * contact you concerning your application, results, and of any events, invitations associated with your results;
  * identify potential [prize eligibility](https://canadacouncil.ca/funding/prizes): 
    * from funded applicants to Council’s programs; or
    * from forms submitted by third parties to a Canada Council program.
  * [proactively disclose recipients](https://canadacouncil.ca/about/public-accountability/proactive-disclosure/grant-recipients) and publish information about the funds distributed;
  * serve as an additional pool of [potential peer assessors](https://canadacouncil.ca/funding/funding-decisions);
  * provide authorized employees access to perform business, technical or professional activities in fulfillment of the Council’s mandate;
  * plan, measure, evaluate, monitor, review and audit programs, or conduct research about the Council’s activities and impacts;
  * generate mailing lists to communicate with you about Canada Council activities, conferences, summits, and to invite you to participate in surveys or other research activities.

Types of personal information and retention:[ Personal Information Banks](https://canadacouncil.ca/about/public-accountability/info-source) CC PPU 130; CC ART 020; CC PPU 115: CC ART 201; CC ART 202; CC PPU 203; CC PPU 204 

### When you [create an account](https://canadacouncil.ca/funding/grants/guide/create-your-account) using the [online portal](https://apply.canadacouncil.ca/?_ga=2.154768696.1619376462.1548165805-1996032459.1462803336)  

The account you create is:

  * password protected and provides access to the portal and your protected content;
  * allows you to register a profile and upload your résumé or curriculum vitae;
  * validated by program staff against the profile’s eligibility criteria before you can apply to program components;
  * allows program staff to contact you concerning your profile validation; and
  * used to create a unique contact identification number linked to your application history and contact information.

Types of personal information and retention:[ Personal Information Banks](https://canadacouncil.ca/about/public-accountability/info-source) CC PPU 130; CC ART 020; CC PPU 115: CC ART 201; CC ART 202; CC PPU 203; CC PPU 204 

### When you apply for a position, or nominate to one of our committees (such as the [peer assessment committee](https://canadacouncil.ca/funding/funding-decisions/decision-making-process)), commissions (PLR, CCUNESCO), or advisory groups.

Information you provide is used to:

  * assess your qualifications and areas of knowledge;
  * make a decision on whom to appoint to a position; or
  * invite you to join a committee, commission, or advisory group.

For positions at the Council, we may ask you to:

  * complete tests or occupational personality profile questionnaires;
  * attend an interview; or
  * complete a combination of these, and we may take interview notes.

Information may be shared with:

  * our selection committee;
  * third parties involved in the recruitment process; or
  * recruitment online application processor, (see the service provider’s privacy notice for safeguards: [Indeed](https://ca.indeed.com/legal)).

Self-identification information is used for employment equity purposes to report workforce representation when applying for a position; and to fill dedicated positions.

Types of personal information and retention:[ Personal Information Banks](https://www.canada.ca/en/treasury-board-secretariat/services/access-information-privacy/access-information/information-about-programs-information-holdings/standard-classes-records.html) PRN 942; PRN 919; [Personal Information Banks](https://canadacouncil.ca/about/public-accountability/info-source) CC PPU 204 

### When you complete the [voluntary self-identification](https://canadacouncil.ca/funding/grants/guide/create-your-account) information

Applicants, nominees, individuals accepting a prize, peer assessment committee participants, and members of Commissions, committees or advisory groups are invited to complete this form:

  * authorized employees analyze this data to assess whether our programs and services are reaching a diverse range of Canadians;
  * disclosure controls will be applied;
  * this information is not used to assess your application and will remain private.

Types of personal information and retention:[ Personal Information Bank](https://canadacouncil.ca/about/public-accountability/info-source) CC PPU 203 

### When you make an enquiry or provide [public feedback](https://canadacouncil.ca/about/public-accountability/public-feedback)  

We use the information you provide to consider and respond to your comments, suggestions, compliments, complaints or query; and for audit purposes.

Types of personal information and retention:[ Personal Information Bank](https://www.canada.ca/en/treasury-board-secretariat/services/access-information-privacy/access-information/information-about-programs-information-holdings/standard-classes-records.html#prn919) PRN 938 

### When you subscribe to our mailing list

With your consent, we use your contact information to communicate with you about Canada Council activities, program updates, initiatives, conferences, summits, and to invite you to participate in surveys using your contact information;

  * to opt-out of these communications, use the unsubscribe link in any email message or contact [web@canadacouncil.ca](mailto:web@canadacouncil.ca) . However, if you are an applicant to a Council program or activity you cannot opt-out from messages related to those activities.

Types of personal information and retention:[ Personal Information Bank](https://www.canada.ca/en/treasury-board-secretariat/services/access-information-privacy/access-information/information-about-programs-information-holdings/standard-classes-records.html#prn919) PRN 938 

### When you participate in a survey or research project

With your consent, survey information is sent to the contact information provided;

  * surveys managed directly by the Canada Council may use third party software such as [Checkbox](https://www.checkbox.com/privacy_policy/). We recommend you review the Privacy Policy of the service provider.
  * surveys may be undertaken by third party service providers on our behalf;
  * third party service must sign a contract respecting the _Privacy Act_ , confidentiality and restrict use of the data collected;
  * completed surveys are processed for purposes of informing our policies, or other work in the subject area of the request for views;
  * you may also be contacted for other types of primary data collection (i.e., focus groups or interviews);
  * we may publish a summary of the responses; and
  * in some instances, the responses themselves may be published but will not contain personal information.

Types of personal information and retention:[ Personal Information Bank](https://www.canada.ca/en/treasury-board-secretariat/services/access-information-privacy/access-information/information-about-programs-information-holdings/standard-classes-records.html#prn919) PRN 938 

### When you [donate](https://canadacouncil.ca/funding/prizes/donors#more) to the Canada Council for the Arts

When you contribute by direct gifts, bequests, life insurance policies, and gifts in kind, your personal information, with your consent, may be used for the purposes of:

  * recognition for your contributions through communications including invitations to award ceremonies;
  * in the Canada Council's Annual Report;
  * on our website;
  * in news releases; and
  * through social media campaigns that promote the awards.

Types of personal information and retention:[ Personal Information Bank](https://canadacouncil.ca/about/public-accountability/info-source) CC ART 202 

### When you access the Canada Council websites.

See the _Canada Council Website Terms and Conditions_

### When you respond to an [RFP](https://canadacouncil.ca/about/requests-for-proposals), RFQ or [contracting services](https://canadacouncil.ca/about/public-accountability/proactive-disclosure/disclosure-of-contracts)  

We collected your personal information when contracting to:

  * enable us to evaluate tenders, and make a decision;
  * contact you about your proposal or contract;
  * to assure contractual obligations are fulfilled

The Canada Council may rely on third party service providers to supply services requiring the service provider to collect, create, use, disclose or store personal information on behalf of the Canada Council.  Personal information may be shared with contractors to provide limited services to the Canada Council;

Contractors are not authorized to use your information for any purpose other than delivering the services that have been requested by the Canada Council in accordance with the Canada Council's instructions and authorization. Violations of the contractual agreement may result in termination of the contract.

Types of personal information and retention:[ Personal Information Bank](https://canadacouncil.ca/about/public-accountability/info-source) PSU 912 

[_Info Source_](https://canadacouncil.ca/about/public-accountability/info-source) _is an inventory of the Canada Council’s information holdings and describes the personal information under its control.   _[_Personal information banks_](https://www.canada.ca/en/treasury-board-secretariat/services/access-information-privacy/access-information/information-about-programs-information-holdings/standard-personal-information-banks.html) _(PIBs) refer to how personal information is collected, used, disclosed, retained and/or disposed of in the administration of Canada Council's programs or activities._

## We use your personal information to meet the Canada Council’s obligations to:

  * enhance transparency, oversight and accountability of public resources through routinely publishing data for public reference: [Corporate Reports](https://canadacouncil.ca/about/governance/corporate-reports), [performance measurement](https://canadacouncil.ca/research), and [Canadian Arts Data](https://canadacouncil.ca/research/data-tables)  

  * proactively disclose financial and human resources-related information to strengthen transparency and oversight of public resources. For a description of these disclosures, visit the following web pages: 

  * plan, evaluate and review programs, in audits, and for generating statistics for these activities: [statistical reporting, studies, and issue and trend analysis](https://canadacouncil.ca/research), determination of [strategic](https://canadacouncil.ca/funding/strategic-funds) funds, and [one-time and recurring initiatives](https://canadacouncil.ca/initiatives) and [commitments](https://canadacouncil.ca/commitments);
  * may share your information with the Canada Revenue Agency (CRA) for the administration of the [Income Tax Act](http://laws-lois.justice.gc.ca/eng/acts/I-3.3/):.

Types of personal information and retention:

[Personal Information Banks](https://canadacouncil.ca/about/public-accountability/info-source) PSU 931; PSU 932; PSU 912

  * comply with applicable laws or regulatory requirements, search warrants, subpoenas or court orders; to investigate unauthorized attempts to access, alter or delete data, the spreading of viruses and other illegal intrusions

## We disclose your personal information under the following conditions:

You should be aware that, subject to any applicable exemptions in the [_Access to Information Act_](http://laws-lois.justice.gc.ca/eng/acts/a-1/) or the [_Privacy Act_](http://laws-lois.justice.gc.ca/eng/acts/P-21/index.html) _,_ information in your application (including support material or confidential information concerning another party) may be disclosed in response to a [request for access](https://canadacouncil.ca/about/public-accountability/access-to-information-and-privacy-acts). If you consider certain portions of your completed application to be confidential clearly identify in writing the material considered confidential. Information you have identified as confidential may not be considered confidential under the requirements of the [_Access to Information Act_](http://laws-lois.justice.gc.ca/eng/acts/a-1/) and may still be subject to release upon request under that Act.

When disclosing personal information, any disclosure will be in accordance with this Privacy Notice and the _Privacy Act_. The Canada Council may use the information you provide for policy analysis, research and/or evaluation activities. Disclosure controls will be applied in these activities.

We do not sell personal information about you to anyone.

Information Sharing Initiatives

To achieve its objectives, the Canada Council may, at times, share information you give us to coordinate programs with other government or funding bodies to assist with research, reporting, program planning and evaluation, or to provide networking or economic opportunities. ([ _Canada Council for the Arts Act_](https://laws-lois.justice.gc.ca/eng/acts/C-2/FullText.html) s. 8(1)(a)).

The Canada Council requires written contracts or agreements with third parties to protect privacy.  These documents address access control, securing data, limitation to its use and retention practices when personal information is to be shared.

In general, personal information may be shared with federal, provincial or territorial government, municipal governments, partners, and authorized third-party service providers; and specifically with those institutions   that have a relation to the arts and culture such as:

## Consent

What happens if you refuse to provide your information

The Canada Council collects your personal information in the ways described in this Privacy Notice and throughout its collection process. If you choose not to provide your information to us, we may not be able to:

  * assess your application, or nomination, deeming it ineligible;
  * respond to your request; or
  * award funds.

Without your consent to collect, use and disclose your personal information the Canada Council is unable to provide you with information or services.

By choosing to provide personal information to the Canada Council or by using this website, you are consenting to the collection, use, disclosure, retention, management and processing of your personal information for the purposes explained in an application process of a program or as explained in this Privacy Notice. Please ensure that all information that you provide is true, accurate and complete.

Wherever possible, we seek a person’s consent before we collect their personal information. The form of consent may vary depending on the circumstances and the type of information being requested. Consent can be express or implied, and can be provided directly by the individual or by an authorized representative.

We will not use your personal information without your consent unless it is either:

  * for the same purpose for which the information was originally collected or compiled;
  * consistent with that purpose; or
  * for a purpose that may be disclosed under section 8(2) of the _Privacy Act_.

## How do we protect your personal information

The Canada Council uses well-established technology to protect the security of your online personal information and your personal content through appropriate administrative, technical and physical security measures and safeguards.  The Canada Council follows industry best practices to make sure it is not inappropriately lost, misused, accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed.

The level of safeguards used to protect personal information will depend on the:

  * sensitivity of the personal information;
  * amount, distribution and format of the information; and
  * method of storage.

The Canada Council follows the [Policy on Government Security](https://www.tbs-sct.gc.ca/pol/doc-eng.aspx?id=16578) and any other federal direction or guidance on information technology security.

The Canada Council employs methods of protection that include:

  * employee training on privacy and the protection of personal information;
  * granting access to information on a “need-to-know” basis;
  * technical measures such as passwords, audit trails, encryption, firewalls and other technical security safeguards;
  * online portal encryption using secure socket layer technology (an SSL certificate), protecting passwords and profile information; users should look for this cue when entering sensitive personal information;
  * physical measures such as locked filing cabinets, restricted access to our offices and other areas where personal information is stored;
  * as part of the peer assessment process, all peer committee members are advised of Council’s expectations for confidentiality and must sign a non-disclosure form;
  * employees are required to sign non-disclosure forms;

  * all individuals or organizations hired under contract or other means to conduct business on behalf of the Canada Council are required to respect the provisions of the _Privacy Act_ as well as this Privacy Notice and related internal policies; and

Personal information may be shared with appropriate law enforcement authorities if suspected criminal activities are detected.

While we are committed to maintaining the security of your information, you play an important role in helping us meet this obligation. Never reveal your username, password or authentication question to anyone.

**Monitoring and evaluation**

Measuring compliance with this Privacy Notice is part of the Canada Council’s internal reviews.

**Privacy Breach**

A privacy breach is the loss of, unauthorized access to, or disclosure of personal information. This may be result of theft, loss of information, data storage equipment, improper or unauthorized collection, use, disclosure, access, storage or disposal of information, including misdirected correspondence.  When the Canada Council discovers or is made aware of a breach, immediate action is taken in compliance with the [Government of Canada’s Directive on Privacy Practices](https://www.tbs-sct.gc.ca/pol/doc-eng.aspx?id=18309) and the [Guidelines for Privacy Breaches](https://www.tbs-sct.gc.ca/pol/doc-eng.aspx?id=26154).

## Retention and destruction of your personal information

Personal information is retained in accordance with federal legislative requirements, such as the[ Library and Archives Act](http://laws-lois.justice.gc.ca/eng/acts/L-7.7/index.html) (s. 7d, 12) and the _Privacy Act_ (s. 4; 5; 6). Following the recommended timeframe, the information is disposed of in accordance with the _Library and Archives Act_ (s. 9; 12).

The Canada Council's retention & disposition guidelines are intended to ensure that records are available for decision-making and are then either stored for historical purposes or disposed of after legal and operational obligations have been met. The retention, disposition and destruction of personal information, is made in accordance with the [Government of Canada’s Directive on Privacy Practices](https://www.tbs-sct.gc.ca/pol/doc-eng.aspx?id=18309).
